STEPHEN CHARLES

OVERVIEW

PORTFOLIO Proficient pythonista with a background in mathematics and computer science. Particular expertise in managing software pipelines and large data sets involving time series analysis and machine learning algorithms, in addition to interpersonal skills from a range of hospitality roles.

EMPLOYMENT

2022 - Now Innovative Technologies - Manchester

Position Machine Learning Engineer, Placement

Stack Python, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Git, Bash

Duties • ICU performs accurate age verification to automate the policy and allow access to age restricted purchases and premises.

• With AI algorithms developed over many years, ICU offers an accurate (99.88%) precise and affordable facial recognition system.

2019 - 2020 Facebook – London - Remote

Position Data Scientist, Analytics Intern

STACK Tableau, SQL, Python

Duties • Performed large-scale data analysis to extract useful business insights.

• Identified the ones which were actionable, suggesting recommendations, and influenced the direction of the business by communicating the results to cross-functional groups.

• Classified leads so that the team could work on the most valuable cases, and suggested improvements in the tools and techniques to help scale the team.

EDUCATION

2021 - 2023 Data Science, University of Bath

MSc Master of Computer Science

STACK Python, SQL, Pytorch, Keras, Tensorflow, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib, Seaborn

RESEARCH Signal processing in neuroscience applications using state-of-the-art statistical machine learning techniques. Specifically, multi-sensory time-series signals are collected and modelled under a Bayesian framework. Techniques such as Gaussian processes, recurrent neural networks and probabilistic sampling methods are used to perform parameter estimation, decision making, and

uncertainty quantification.

2020 - 2021 Astronomy and Astrophysics, University of Manchester

MSc Distinction, Master of Physics

Stack Python, Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Git, Bash

RESEARCH Published a program to facilitate the data acquisition and analysis pipeline for TESS automatically, dubbed firefly, which applies nested sampling (dynesty) to find best fit variables (TransitFit)

between the host star and exoplanet.

2016 - 2020 Mathematics with Computer Science, University of Nottingham

MMATH Upper Second-Class Honours, Master of Mathematics

Stack C++, Python, R, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Research Dissertation involved working with python to numerically solve spherical cavitation bubble collapse.

 ${\bf 2014-2016}\quad {\bf Space\ Engineering}, {\it Loughborough\ College}$

Linux, Windows, Mac

A-Levels Mathematics A* · Further Mathematics A · Physics A · Engineering A

A specialised course focused on Engineering with guest lectures at the Space Centre in Leicester.

GENERAL TECH STACK

Systems

AWARDS AND QUALIFICATIONS

LANGUAGE	Python, C++, LATEX, SQL	$\boldsymbol{2022}$	DataCamp: Data Science Track
PACKAGES	Numpy, Pandas, SciPy, AstroPy	2021	Kaggle Expert
ML PACKAGES	Sklearn, Tensorflow, PyTorch	$\boldsymbol{2020}$	Tableau Desktop Specialist
W_{EB}	HTML, Markdown, CSS	2016	Full UK Driving Licence
SCIENTIFIC	Matlab, R, Fortran, Mathematica	2015	Grade 8 Violin
SOFTWARE	Microsoft Office, Tableau, Blender		

Publications

Author

Co-Author Hayes, J J C, E Kerins, J S Morgan et al. (2021) "TransitFit: an exoplanet transit fitting package

for multi-telescope datasets and its application to WASP-127 b, WASP-91 b, and WASP-126

b", 1–14.

ACADEMIC WORK EXPERIENCE

AUTUMN 2018 The University of Singapore

EXPERIENCE Obtained a scholarship to study a crash course in Korean language for 5 weeks and to learn about

the culture and history of the changing landscapes of Singapore. Upon completion, applied to spend

the Autumn semester here successfully.

Space Research Centre, The University of Leicester July 2014

EXPERIENCE During my first college year I gained work experience at the University of Leicester Space Research

Centre, assisting in the development of an astrobiology rock-sampling tool called SPLIT for use on

Mars.

Positions and Responsibilities

2018 - 2019 Mature Student Mentor, UoN 2017 - 2018 Ambassador, UoN

> I was a point of contact for mature students, helping them settle in and

be there is a support capacity.

presented, and gave advice to prospective students.

Public Speaking

2017Department of Physics, The University of Nottingham

Gave introductions to guest speakers and shout outs in lectures to ensure everyone is informed of important events.

2014Space Research Centre, The University of Leicester

Presented my findings to a crowd of 50 post doc students and an astronaut! My presentation was based on exoplanet research and the feasibility of alien civilizations to be space faring.

Volunteering

2017 Magical Maths - Nottingham

Role Organisation of weekly sessions to promote mathematics to primary school children, in line with

the national curriculum.

2016 Workaway - Ghana I volunteered at a remote school in Africa for a turn of 2 months, to teach those with no access Role

to maths the fundamentals. I managed to organise a bus to take everyone attending to places of historic interest, and demonstrate how the maths they had learned in the classroom has real impact

and use to the world around them.

Interests

PHOTOGRAPHY Music Avid adventurer and keen

astronomer. This hobby pushes the

boundaries of my interest in both.

Surviving extreme conditions makes HIKING

me feel alive.

Self taught Guitar, Piano, Violin. GENERAL Science fiction and anything spacey.

REFERENCES

References can be supplied on request.